# JOSHUA PETERS

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

(320)293-1372



PETERS-L-JOSHUA 👩 JOSHUALPETERS



PETERS.L.JOSHUA@GMAIL.COM

Experienced business owner with a strong background in marketing applications, collaborating with indie developers, AAA publishers, and startups across the globe. A self-starter who takes initiative and follows through with employer partners while providing excellence in the workplace.

#### **CORE SKILLS**

JAVA SE HTML MYSQL CSS SPRING BOOT JAVASCRIPT JAVA EE FRAMEWORK JQUERY BOOTSTRAP **OBJECT ORIENTED** VCS WITH GIT PROGRAMMING PAIRED PARTNER THYMELEAF PROGRAMMING

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **TWITCH TV** Partnered Broadcaster

2014 - 2019

Produced, scheduled, and broadcasted video content to a remote website on a weekly or daily basis. Analyzed audience retention data and viewer trends to produce targeted content, and changed content to reflect audience demands. Worked directly with developers providing player feedback to help shape the future of the game and to solve existing problems.

#### **VERIZON WIRELESS** CSR / RSR

2007 - 2008

Harnessed initiative and resourcefulness to generate additional revenue by leveraging strong interpersonal skills and communication to up-sell during point of sale. Promoted to a sales position from customer service after a year of hire from excellent performance and exceeding all metrics.

## MILITARY EXPERIENCE

#### **US AIR FORCE** Maintenance Journeyman

2009 - 2014

Fully trained in Aerospace Ground Equipment (AGE) and Precision Measurement Equipment Laboratory (PMEL). Deployed to Ali Al Saleem Air Force Base and supported mission Iraqi Freedom. Diligent driver dispatched 200+ units; lauded by flight-line expediters. 100% completion on all quality assurance tests. Graduated basic training as an honor graduate.

### **DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

ADLISTER **JAN 2020** 

Used Java to dynamically generate HTML pages and to interact with a MySQL database. Utilized Model-View-Controller paradigm while understanding the request-response lifecycle of HTTP requests to develop an intuitive application. Created a unique Adlister branding for the Texas communities and provided multiple use case scenarios for the application to emulate an authentic user experience.

#### PERSONAL WEBSITE

**NOV 2019** 

A fully built website summarizing all projects and job history. Used bootstrap, HTML, and CSS to publish site on github. You can view the site here: joshualpeters.github.io

**MOVIE LIST NOV 2019** 

Initialized JSON database to load into the site with ajax. On page load generates HTML from JSON responses. Iterated through a complex API to retrieve specific information. Merged to Github while rotating with paired partner programming.

#### **OCT 2019 WEATHER MAP**

Learned how to use Mapbox and Darksky APIs and developed an interactive weather map for any known address. Wrote javaScript code so both APIs work in parallel and build a working software program from scratch alone.

#### **COFFEE SHOP OCT 2019**

Developed search capabilities to interact with website and iterated through data structures primarily of which were arrays. Designed a professional product using Bootstrap Grid and used DOM to dynamically update the page upon interaction.

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

#### CODEUP CERTIFICATE OF COMPLETION

**FEB 2020** 

A fully-immersive, project based, and intensive 20 week full stack Java career accelerator that provides students with 670 hours of expert instruction in software development.